- Are you ready, kids?
- 孩子们，你们准备好了吗？
all:
Aye, aye, Captain!
全部：
是啊是啊，队长！
- I can't hear you.
- 我听不到你说话。
all:
Aye, aye, Captain!
全部：
是啊是啊，队长！
- ♪ Ohh... ♪
- ♪ 哦...♪
♪ Who lives in a pineapple
under the sea? ♪
♪ 谁住在菠萝里
在海底？ ♪
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- ♪ Absorbent and yellow
and porous is he ♪
- ♪ 吸水性和黄色
他是多孔的 ♪
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- ♪ If nautical nonsense
be something you wish ♪
- ♪ 如果航海废话
成为你想要的东西♪
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- ♪ Then drop on the deck
and flop like a fish ♪
- ♪ 然后落在甲板上
然后像鱼一样扑通扑通♪
all: SpongeBob SquarePants!
- Ready?
所有：海绵宝宝！
- 准备好？
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
SpongeBob SquarePants!
- SpongeBob
- 海绵宝宝
SquarePants!
方裤！
[laughing]
[笑]
♪ ♪
[waves crashing]
[海浪拍打]
[dramatic music]
[戏剧音乐]
♪ ♪
- This is a Bikini Bottom News
special report.
- 这是比基尼泳裤新闻
特别报告。
Perch?
- Perch Perkins here
栖息？
- 鲈鱼帕金斯在这里
at the Bikini Bottom
power plant,
在比基尼底部
发电厂,
where the evil super villain
known as the Dirty Bubble,
邪恶的超级恶棍在哪里
被称为肮脏的泡沫，
has finally been
cornered by police!
终于被
被警察围堵！
- [groaning]
- [呻吟]
- Stand back, coppers,
and cease your attack,
-退后一步，铜人，
并停止你的攻击，
or I'll make your police chief
my late night snack!
不然我就让你当警察局长
我的夜宵！
[laughs]
[笑]
- [groans]
- [呻吟]
Do what he says!
按他说的做！
[groans]
[呻吟]
- Will the grime
of this evil soap globe
- 污垢会吗
这个邪恶的肥皂地球
wash over our fair city?
淹没我们美丽的城市？
Or will the law force him
to clean up his act?
还是法律会强迫他
来洗白他的行为？
- [screams]
- [尖叫]
- Or will he choose
door number three,
- 或者他会选择
三号门，
and devour a newsman
live on TV?
并吞噬一名新闻记者
电视直播？
[laughs]
[笑]
- [groans]
- [呻吟]
[groaning]
[呻吟]
- Drop him, airhead!
- 放下他，笨蛋！
- [yells]
- [大喊]
Yike!
哎呀！
[screams]
[尖叫声]
- I got him!
- 我抓到他了！
- Remember this face
and remember it well,
- 记住这张脸
并且牢牢记住，
so you'll recognize me
when I see you in--
这样你就会认出我
当我看到你在——
- Jail!
- 监狱！
[jazzy music]
[爵士乐]
- [groans]
- [呻吟]
[jazzy music]
[爵士乐]
- [exhales]
- [呼气]
[grunts]
[咕哝]
♪ ♪
[exhales]
[呼气]
- Thank you, warden.
I feel like a new bubble.
- 谢谢你，典狱长。
我感觉就像一个新的泡沫。
- Remember, Bubble, keep it
clean, or you'll get mean.
- 记住，泡泡，保留它
干净，否则你会变得卑鄙。
- [laughs]
- [笑]
Thank you, warden.
I promise I won't let you down!
谢谢你，典狱长。
我保证我不会让你失望的！
- Here's the address
of your new job.
- 这是地址
你的新工作。
- [groans]
- [呻吟]
♪ ♪
I'll make you proud,
warden.
我会让你感到骄傲，
典狱长。
Stay clean or you'll get mean.
A new life.
保持干净，否则你会变得卑鄙。
新的生活。
No more dirt,
and no more wrong turns.
不再有污垢，
不再走错路。
[grunts]
[咕哝]
The Krusty Krab.
Hm, this must be the place!
蟹堡王。
嗯，一定是这个地方！
[whooshing]
[呼啸]
Oh, I can't thank you enough
for this job, Mr. Krabs.
哦，我对你感激不尽
对于这份工作，蟹老板。
What would you like me to do?
Greet people at the door?
你想让我做什么？
到门口跟人打招呼吗？
Serve the food?
- Oh, no.
上菜吗？
- 哦，不。
I've got a special job
我有一份特殊的工作
that needs someone
with your special talents.
需要有人
凭借你的特殊才能。
You're on dirty dish detail.
你正在处理脏盘子的细节。
[dramatic music]
[戏剧音乐]
- D-d-d-d-dirty dishes?
- 脏-脏-脏-脏盘子？
Wait, couldn't I just work
the cash register or something?
等等，我不能只是工作吗？
收银机什么的？
- Listen, I hired a
dish-washing bubble
- 听着，我雇了一个
洗碗泡沫
to save money on soap,
and I want these plates
为了省肥皂钱，
我想要这些盘子
sparkling by
lunchtime, savvy?
闪闪发光
午餐时间，懂事吗？
- Just call me Sparkles.
- 就叫我闪闪吧。
- [humming]
- [嗡嗡声]
- Oh!
- 哦！
♪ ♪
[gulps]
[吞咽]
Oh!
哦！
Stay clean, or you'll get mean.
保持干净，否则你会变得卑鄙。
[door squeaks]
[门吱吱作响]
♪ ♪
Huh.
呵呵。
- [grunting]
- [咕哝]
Brr, is there a blizzard
coming in?
Brr，有暴风雪吗
进来吗？
Because I've got a cold front.
因为我有冷锋。
[laughter]
[笑声]
- Oh, hi, I didn't
see you there.
-哦，嗨，我没有
那里见。
You must be the new dishwasher.
你一定是新来的洗碗机。
Welcome aboard.
I'm SpongeBob!
欢迎登机。
我是海绵宝宝！
- Hi, SpongeBob, I'm, uh--
DB, yeah, DB.
- 嗨，海绵宝宝，我是，呃--
数据库，是的，数据库。
- Oh, we're going to have
so much fun, DB!
- 哦，我们将会有
太有趣了，DB！
We'll be galley pallies!
我们将成为厨房伙计！
[bell dings]
[铃声]
Whoops, back to work.
哎呀，回去工作吧。
[vocalizing]
[发声]
- Keep it clean
or you'll get mean,
- 保持清洁
不然你会变得刻薄
Keep it clean
or you'll get mean.
保持清洁
否则你会变得刻薄。
Hm?
嗯？
[gasps]
[喘气]
Hey, I did it!
I got dirty
嘿，我做到了！
我弄脏了
and I didn't turn evil.
Huh, I must be cured!
我并没有变得邪恶。
呵呵，一定要治好啊！
[humming]
[嗡嗡声]
[dramatic music]
[戏剧音乐]
Scraping up filth
from between every crack.
刮掉污物
从每一条裂缝之间。
I'm the Dirty Bubble
and baby, I'm back.
我是肮脏的泡泡
宝贝，我回来了。
[laughs]
[笑]
- Oh, what can I get
you, Dirty Bubble?
- 哦，我能得到什么
你，脏泡泡？
[screams]
[尖叫声]
The Dirty Bubble!
Where's that nice DB?
肮脏的泡泡！
这么好的数据库在哪里？
What did you do to him,
you super filthy super villain?
你对他做了什么
你是超级肮脏的超级恶棍吗？
- [laughs]
- [笑]
- [yells]
- [大喊]
♪ ♪
What did you do with DB?
你用DB做了什么？
[groaning]
[呻吟]
[laughs]
[笑]
- DB is short for
Dirty Bubble, isn't it?
- DB 是缩写
肮脏的泡泡，不是吗？
- Yes, SpongeBob, it's me.
- 是的，海绵宝宝，是我。
I'm trying to change
my evil ways and stay clean.
我正在努力改变
我的恶行并保持清洁。
- Wow, a super-villain
intervention!
- 哇，超级反派
干预！
I'll help you, DB.
我会帮助你的，DB。
I'll make sure you stay
squeaky clean and dirt free!
我会确保你留下来
干净整洁，无污垢！
- [laughs]
- [笑]
- Front and center, Mr. Bubble.
I got another job for you.
- 前面和中间，泡泡先生。
我为你找到了另一份工作。
[bubbles pop]
[气泡破裂]
Now, this new job is very
exclusive and very French.
现在，这个新工作非常
独特且非常法国。
- Ooh, la, la.
- 哦，啦，啦。
- [grunts]
- [咕哝]
Eau de toilette.
- What, oh, sacre-pew!
淡香水。
- 什么，哦，圣座！
- Make it sparkle.
- 让它闪闪发光。
[hums]
[哼哼]
- Okay, he's gone.
- 好吧，他走了。
Don't worry about
those toilets, DB.
不用担心
那些厕所，DB。
[grunts]
[咕哝]
I will clean them for you.
"Toot suite," mon ami.
我会帮你清理它们。
“嘟嘟套房，”我的朋友。
[laughs]
[笑]
[toilet flushes]
[厕所冲水]
- Dirt, dirt.
Beautiful dirt!
- 污垢，污垢。
美丽的污垢！
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
- "Zoot alors!"
DB?
- “祖特阿洛斯！”
数据库？
[gasps]
[喘气]
Incoming!
来袭！
- [laughs]
- [笑]
♪ Alla-wetta,
all of you are wet-ta ♪
♪ 阿拉维塔，
你们都湿了♪
♪ Alla-wetta, all of you
are soaked ♪
♪ 阿拉维塔，你们所有人
都湿透了♪
[dramatic music]
[戏剧音乐]
- [screams]
- [尖叫]
- Pow, hold onto your shirty.
Here comes the dirty.
- 战俘，抓紧你的衬衫。
脏东西来了。
[gargles]
[漱口]
Thanks for keeping
me clean, SpongeBob.
感谢您的保留
我干净了，海绵宝宝。
- Don't worry, DB.
We just needed
- 别担心，DB。
我们只需要
to wash away
that stinking thinking.
洗掉
那个臭想法。
- For weeks,
SpongeBob worked with DB
- 几个星期以来，
海绵宝宝与DB合作
to stay clean and good!
保持干净和良好！
- [groans]
- [呻吟]
- Ta-da!
- 哒哒！
- [laughs]
- [笑]
[groovy music]
[动听的音乐]
[washing machine whirrs]
【洗衣机嗡嗡作响】
♪ ♪
[screaming]
[尖叫]
- Yeah!
- 是的！
[laughs]
[笑]
- Ah!
- 啊！
[laughter]
[笑声]
- [snoring]
- [打鼾]
- [whistles]
- [口哨]
Enjoy those patties!
享受那些肉饼吧！
[laughs]
[笑]
- Well, DB,
it looks like you're cured.
- 嗯，DB，
看起来你已经痊愈了。
You haven't been dirty
in weeks.
你没有脏过
几周后。
- Thanks to you, SpongeBob,
I'll never be dirty again.
- 谢谢你，海绵宝宝，
我再也不会脏了。
[laughs]
[笑]
- Oh, speaking of dirty.
- 哦，说到肮脏。
[grunts]
[咕哝]
Ew!
呃！
[dramatic music]
[戏剧音乐]
- [grunting]
- [咕哝]
♪ ♪
[laughter]
[笑声]
You want me clean,
but I ain't willing.
你要我干净，
但我不愿意。
I got to be me,
and me is a villain!
我必须是我，
而我就是一个恶棍！
[laughter]
[笑声]
- Aw, that's nice.
He found his rainbow.
- 噢，那很好。
他找到了属于他的彩虹。
- Uh-oh.
- 呃哦。
- The Dirty Bubble
has been seen everywhere,
- 肮脏的泡泡
已经随处可见，
defiling dozens of decent
denizens with dirty deeds!
玷污了几十个正派
做了肮脏勾当的居民！
[both singing]
[两人都在唱歌]
[slurping]
[发出声音]
[both yelp]
[两人都尖叫]
both: Clean?
两人：干净吗？
[crying]
[哭泣]
[jaunty music]
[欢快的音乐]
- So I says to the scallywag,
"listen, here you--"
- 所以我对那些恶棍说，
“听着，你在这里——”
- [laughs]
- [笑]
- It's time to
have tea and cakes.
- 是时候了
喝茶和蛋糕。
- Get him!
- 抓住他！
[clamoring]
[叫喊]
[yelling]
[大喊]
[whooshing]
[呼啸]
all: Yay!
全体：耶！
[laughter]
[笑声]
all: Aw.
全体：噢。
- Yes, Billy, two plus two
still equals four.
- 是的，比利，二加二
仍然等于四。
- [laughs]
- [笑]
[laughter]
[笑声]
- [mumbling]
- [咕哝]
- Breaking news:
The Dirty Bubble
- 突发新闻：
肮脏的泡沫
just wiped all the teacher's
dirty looks
刚刚把老师的都擦掉了
肮脏的外表
right off their faces!
Who will be next?
就在他们脸上！
下一个会是谁？
- [laughs]
- [笑]
No more pencils,
no more books,
不再有铅笔，
不再有书了，
no more news guy's dirty looks.
不再有新闻人的肮脏外表。
[laughs]
[笑]
- No!
- 不！
[groans]
[呻吟]
Oh, that got in my mouth!
哦，那东西到我嘴里了！
- [laughs]
- [笑]
[groans]
[呻吟]
- Sorry, old chum,
but from now on,
- 对不起，老朋友，
但从现在开始，
you're going to have
to stay clean for good.
你将会有
永远保持清洁。
- Begone, hygiene.
I'm too big to stay clean!
- 走开，讲卫生。
我太大了，无法保持干净！
[laughter]
[笑声]
- Ah!
- 啊！
[groaning]
[呻吟]
- [laughs]
- [笑]
Ow!
It's on now.
噢！
现在已经开始了
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
♪ ♪
[yells]
[喊叫]
- [laughs]
- [笑]
- [grunting]
- [咕哝]
Help, help!
Call the cops!
救命，救命！
报警！
Call Mr. Krabs!
Call my mommy!
给蟹老板打电话吧！
叫我妈妈！
- [grunts]
- [咕哝]
- I think for dessert,
I'll eat more dirt!
- 我觉得甜点
我要吃更多的泥土！
[laughs]
[笑]
- Not Goo Lagoon!
- 不是古泻湖！
[clamoring]
[叫喊]
And to my beloved pet, Gary,
I bequeath my pineapple
还有我心爱的宠物加里，
我遗赠我的菠萝
and my tool shed and
my mailbox and Patrick.
和我的工具棚和
我的邮箱和帕特里克。
[cries]
[哭声]
What?
Wow.
什么？
哇。
Sometimes, I forget
just how absorbent I am!
有时，我会忘记
我的吸收力多么强啊！
[yelps]
[尖叫声]
- Wait, what?
Oh, stop spinning, you sponge.
- 等等，什么？
哦，别再旋转了，你这个海绵。
You're stealing my grunge.
你偷了我的垃圾。
Uh, uh, stuff that rhymes!
Ah!
呃，呃，押韵的东西！
啊!
- [grunts]
- [咕哝]
[burps]
[打嗝]
- I may be a squirt,
but I'm still full of dirt.
- 我可能是个水鬼，
但我还是满身泥土。
[laughs]
[笑]
- Oh, little mini-DB
is so cute.
- 哦，小迷你数据库
太可爱了。
- Ah!
- 啊！
[groovy music]
[动听的音乐]
- We got him!
- 我们抓到他了！
- Every time I wash dishes,
I'll think of you.
- 每次洗碗的时候
我会想你的。
- Hm, every time
I have nightmares,
- 嗯，每次
我做恶梦，
I'll think of you, too.
我也会想你的
- Thank you, citizen.
We'll take it from here.
- 谢谢你，公民。
我们将从这里拿走它。
- It was a dirty job,
but somebody had to do it!
- 这是一项肮脏的工作
但必须有人这么做！
[laughs]
[笑]
[all gasp]
[全都喘气]
- Just kidding!
- 只是在开玩笑！
[laughter]
[笑声]
[sneezes]
[打喷嚏]
[all groaning]
[全都呻吟]
all: Gesundheit.
全部：Gesundheit。
- Thank you.
Got some schmutz on you there.
- 谢谢。
你那里有一些坏事。
[giggles]
[咯咯笑]
[groovy music]
[动听的音乐]
♪ ♪